MIGUEL VILÁ

miguel-vila @ github \(\phi\) miguelvilag@gmail.com \(\phi\) Mobile phone: +44.0744.8026.462

PROFILE

I am an experienced software engineer that has delivered large-scale projects working inside small and large teams. I'm keen to collaborate with others in order to deliver quality solutions.

I have experience with a diverse set of technologies and I'm able to learn new things quickly. Although my focus is on the development side, I'm capable of doing tasks related to infrastructure and operations as well.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Disney Streaming Services

Senior Software Engineer

January 2017 - Present

Manchester, United Kingdom

- · Developed and maintained services related to commerce operations. Collaborated with other teams in order to deliver cross-cutting features.
- · Created proposals for new components as well as designed their architecture. Collaborated with other engineers in order to define the design and behavior of these new components.
- · Designed a new version of a system that would improve the quality of data used in analytics.
- · Developed scalable backend services for user authentication. This included 4 microservices written in Scala, each one with separate responsibilities.
- · Executed performance tests over those services in order to define sensible scaling policies.
- · Helped to establish the project's infrastructure. This included scaling groups, alarms and dashboards.

s4n
Software Engineer

January 2013 - June 2016 Boqotá, Colombia

- · Developed enterprise software for insurance companies. Used a variety of technologies: Java, Scala, JavaScript amongst others.
- · Worked remotely for a company in the United States developing a REST API using Scala.
- · I was the technical leader of a small team of engineers. Guided technical decisions and helped members new to the tech stack or to the team become productive.

Los Andes University

August 2011 - May 2012

Teaching Assistant for Design and analysis of algorithms.

Bogotá, Colombia

· I evaluated student homework and exams. Gave some classes in preparation for exams.

CIACUA, Los Andes University

Software Engineer

March 2011 - August 2011 Boqotá, Colombia

· I worked in the software reingeneering process of an application used for the design and simulation of distributed water networks. I documented the design in UML and fixed bugs found in a version update.

EDUCATION

Recurse Center

August 2016 - November 2016

New York City, United States of America

Self-directed, educational retreat for people who want to get better at programming

Los Andes University

January 2009 - December 2012

Bogotá, Colombia

BSc in Systems and Computing Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

(in order of skill): Scala, Java, Python, Javascript.

Infrastructure: Mostly AWS. Cloudformation, ECS, CloudWatch, DynamoDB.